Namrata Banerjee

Founder-Product Lead

nmalik@alumni.cmu.edu

Summary

I am passionate about solving problems and turning the complex into the simple. I have product experience in B2B and B2C. I have worked in web services, application software, visualization software, middleware, and firmware where I have used Lean Startup and Agile methodologies that support the iterative product development process. These days I am focused on growing my startup, giving shape to another product idea, building a platform that assists in rebuilding the broken lives of women in conflict zones, and advising on a projects. I am a maker, with a bias towards action. If you need help with building products from the ground up, I am happy to connect with you.

Experience

Founder at ConferenceShare

2015 - Present

ConferenceShare is focused on helping conference attendees save money. Built on the simple concept of helping attendees connect with each other so they can share the cost of Airbnb or hotel room, ConferenceShare has generated thousands in consumer surplus since its launch in 2016. We are proud partners of several ACM, IEEE, Quantitative Biology, Sociology, and Performing Arts conferences.

Co-Founder

2017 - Present

Strong Women Strong Minds is focused on helping rebuild the broken lives of women in conflict zones. Please contact us if you are interested in hearing more about what we are doing. https://www.strongwomenstrongminds.org/

Business Consultant at loom

2018 - Present

Part of the Loom team working on the business and finance side of things. Loom helps families create, curate, and share their digital heirlooms.

Information Architect, Team Lead at Rockwell Automation

2011 - 2014 (4 years)

My team and I worked on the visualization layer of an industrial automation software (full stack solution). We supported a cross-functional global team of engineers, designers, and localization developers to understand requirements and define short- and long- term content strategy.

Information Developer, Team Lead at Rockwell Automation

2007 - 2011 (5 years)

My team and I developed user assistance content for application software products. I managed, mentored, reviewed progress of my team, accounting for risks and ambiguity.

Information Developer at Rockwell Software

2004 - 2007 (4 years)

I worked with engineering teams to develop user assistance for middleware and firmware products.

Information Development Intern at Rockwell Software

2003 - 2004 (2 years)

I was information development intern for middleware software products.

Research Assistant Intern at Carnegie Mellon University

2003 - 2003 (1 year)

I was a research assistant for the ThinkTank project. https://www.cmu.edu/thinktank/

Education

University of California, Berkeley, Haas School of Business

Master of Business Administration (M.B.A.), Entrepreneurship & General Management

Activities and Societies: Berkeley Entrepreneurs Association, Finance, Digital Media & Entertainment, & Haas Technology clubs.

Carnegie Mellon University

Master's Degree, English - Professional Writing

Activities and Societies: Society for Technical Communication - User experience, information architecture, emerging technologies. Relevant courses: Communication design, User research, Online information design, Style, Software engineering documentation.

National Institute of Information Technology

Diploma, Computer Software Engineering

Chaudhary Charan Singh University

Bachelor's Degree, Biology

Namrata Banerjee

Founder-Product Lead

nmalik@alumni.cmu.edu



Contact Namrata on LinkedIn